<reference anchor="NBS.RPT.2494" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NBS.RPT.2494">
  <front>
    <title>Propagation of radio waves over land at 1046 MC</title>
    <author fullname="Barsis, A. P.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bean, B. R. (Bradford R.),">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Herbstreit, J. W.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hornberg, K. O.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Norton, Kenneth A.,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>United States.</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The purpose of this report is to present the experimental data on 1046 Mc obtained at the Cheyenne Mountain Field Station for the period February 1, 1952 through January 31, 1953. Continuous recordings were not made prior to this period and consequently any previous data are not considered. In addition, this report includes the analysis of diurnal and seasonal variations in hourly median signal levels, the analysis of variations in instantaneous signal levels and the analysis of prolonged space-wave fade-outs within the radio horizon for the period investigated, an analysis of the effects of irregular terrain at points within the radio horizon, an analysis of the scattered signals at points far beyond the radio horizon, including estimates of the expected effective gains of large antenna arrays, the required spacing for diversity arrays and the effective intelligence bearing bandwidths of the propagation paths. Finally, as a result of a recent investigation of propagation over high mountain ridges, an analysis is presented of the obstacle gains expected on 1000 Mc in mountainous terrain.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NBS.RPT.2494"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NBS report" value="2494"/>
</reference>