<reference anchor="NBS.SP.527" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NBS.SP.527">
  <front>
    <title>Footwear Technology Symposium -- Manufacturing a competitive advantage</title>
    <author fullname="King, Margery H.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>United States.</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The objective of this symposium was to assess manufacturing technologies which could be adapted or developed to provide a competitive advantage for the U.S. footwear industry, and to develop a specific plan for activities that would be appropriate for government and industry cooperation. The meeting was part of a three-year Department of Commerce Program to help restore the growth and vitality of the domestic footwear industry. Initial sessions presented technical and evaluative information as an input to the subsequent working group discussions of footwear industry representatives. Government staff described the results of their assessment of the problems and opportunities of the industry. To stimulate constructive dialogue, five private research organizations presented ideas and recommendations for future footwear technological development resulting from Commerce Department sponsored studies. The major new technologies and processes presented addressed materials development, leather technologies, customfitting and computer assistance in shoe design and manufacture (CAD/CAM). In other presentations, the President of the American Footwear Industry Association shared his concerns, a leading footwear designer explored design, marketing and the technology interfaces, and representatives of technologically advanced industries, (aerospace, automobiles, communications) shared their views on manufacturing technologies and applications to footwear industry problems. Preliminary symposium results were evidence of industry enthusiasm and support for government-industry cooperative activities, interest in establishing a footwear center to provide industry-wide technical assistance, and a desire to assess computer-aided design and manufacture (CAD/CAM). Reports by the consulting firms on new technologies and business strategies for the footwear industry are included as appendices.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NBS.SP.527"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NBS special publication; NBS special pub; NBS SP" value="527"/>
</reference>