<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2293" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2293">
  <front>
    <title>Database-assisted design</title>
    <author fullname="Yeo, DongHun.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pingree, Steve.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sisson, Sophie.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Heumann, Eric.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mashnad, Mehedy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This NIST Technical Note presents a User’s Manual of the DAD_PBD software for mid- and high-rise steel structures. A Database-Assisted Design (DAD) method for the design of tall buildings that utilizes time-varying aerodynamic pressure data from wind tunnel measurements or numerical simulations and wind climate data of the target site has been developed at NIST and has proven effective in the past. As opposed to the analytical method, the DAD approach allows for time-domain and wind directional analyses that could provide the full phase details with higher mode shapes and for a site-specific Performance-Based Design (PBD). However, the approach lacked practicability to structural engineers due to reliance on in-house analysis software intended for research purposes. DAD_BPD software is developed and presented herein, a powerful and user-friendly tool that enables the DAD method to be more accessible to structural engineers by integrating a widely used commercial structural analysis and design software, ETABS. In the past year, MATLAB-based software was first developed but, as recommended by industry partners, now has migrated to Python-based software to increase accessibility to practicing engineers and to improve computational time. The structural and dynamic analyses are performed by ETABS, and the analysis and design of steel members are carried out in Python. DAD_PBD ultimately provides design response curves as a function of mean recurrence intervals (MRIs) of various design parameters, including Demand-to-Capacity Index (DCI), inter-story drift ratio, floor acceleration, and Deformation Damage Index (DDI). The design is iterated until the design responses satisfy the design specification. The User’s Manual includes an example of the application of the software.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2293"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2293"/>
</reference>