<reference anchor="NIST.DCI.004" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.DCI.004">
  <front>
    <title>NIST-NOAA survey tool for business disruption and recovery associated with extreme events :general instrument applied to the Beaumont and Port Arthur, Texas small- and medium-sized business and nonprofit organizations community post-Hurricane Harvey</title>
    <author fullname="Michelle Meyer" initials="M." surname="Meyer">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Joy Semien" initials="J." surname="Semien">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jennifer Helgeson" initials="J." surname="Helgeson">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="August" day="12"/>
    <abstract>To gather more in-depth information about how disasters affect businesses and nonprofits, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) launched a study of business disruption and recovery related to several recent disasters. This report outlines the survey instrument used as the basis for the research designed and conducted in partnership between Texas Sea Grant and the Texas A University Hazard Reduction and Recovery Center (HRRC), NIST Applied Economics Office (AEO), and the NOAA Regional Integrated Sciences and Assessment (RISA) Program. This research protocol uses a mixed-method research approach to study businesses and nonprofit organizations that were impacted by Hurricane Harvey in 2017 and their long-term recovery process. The approach combines both quantitative and qualitative data collection methods of in-person and telephone surveys to obtain organizational disruption and recovery information from organizational owners and managers.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.DCI.004"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST DCI" value="004"/>
</reference>