<reference anchor="NIST.AMS.100-56" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.AMS.100-56">
  <front>
    <title>Powder spreading testbed for studying the powder spreading process in powder bed fusion machines</title>
    <author fullname="Whiting, Justin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Whitenton, Eric">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Das, &#9;Aniruddha.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tondare, Vipin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fox, Jason.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McGlauflin, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Donmez, Alkan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Moylan, Shawn P..">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The spreading of powder is an integral part of powder bed fusion-based additive manufacturing technologies; however, due to the complex nature and the number of interactions between particles, studying the powder spreading process is difficult. In order to gain insight into how the metal powder is spread in the powder bed fusion machines using a recoater, a spreading testbed is needed, which provides a method for recording the powder spreading process and characterizing the powder spread layer. The objective of this testbed is to study and try to establish fundamental relationships between bulk metal powder characteristics and powder spreading performance. Here, a fabrication of a powder spreading testbed (PST) is described. The minimum but necessary functionality of the PST has been discussed. The potential characterization methods for the powder spread layer have been proposed. This document serves as a guideline for the future development of the present testbed.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.AMS.100-56"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST advanced manufacturing series" value="100-56"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST advanced manufacturing series; NIST AMS" value="100-56"/>
</reference>