<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8451" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8451">
  <front>
    <title>Multi’omic characterization of human whole stool RGTMs</title>
    <author fullname="Bayless, Amanda.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Da Silva, Sandra.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Davis, W. Clay.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Cruz, Abraham Kuri.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Piotrowski, Paulina.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Schock, Tracey.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Servetas, Stephanie.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The gut microbiome plays a critical role in a vast and disparate set of health and disease states, including cancer and obesity. Human fecal is a complex mixture including microbes, proteins, undigested plant matter and fat content according to the diet type (e.g., vegan, omnivore). The complexity of human fecal material along with the complexity of the analytical workflow of omics-based techniques makes metabolomics measurements challenging. To address this need, NIST is developing a human stool reference material (RM) to compare and assess reproducibility in omics-based techniques. This report shares the initial characterization of a human stool research grade testing material (RGTM). At NIST, a RGTM is an exploratory material developed to evaluate fit-for-purpose needs within a community. This effort started in 2019 and since then, the manufacturer for the material has changed and protocols to analyze the samples have been optimized. The approaches used to characterize the samples described in this report may or may not be the current approach used on the development of RM 8048. In addition, it should be stated the material used in the RGTM and consequently in the RM is not an authentic representation of human stool as it was pre-processed (homogenized, diluted in water and bottled) after collection for research application.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8451"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8451"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8451"/>
</reference>