<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8394" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8394">
  <front>
    <title>Health assessment measurements quality assurance program :
exercise 6 final report</title>
    <author fullname="Charles Barber" initials="A" surname="Barber">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carolyn Burdette" initials="Q" surname="Burdette">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hugh Hayes" initials="V" surname="Hayes">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Monique Johnson" initials="E" surname="Johnson">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shaun Kotoski" initials="P" surname="Kotoski">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jacolin Murray" initials="A" surname="Murray">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Melissa Phillips" initials="M" surname="Phillips">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Catherine Rimmer" initials="A" surname="Rimmer">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laura Wood" initials="J" surname="Wood">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrea Yarberry" initials="J" surname="Yarberry">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="September" day="20"/>
    <abstract>The Health Assessment Measurements Quality Assurance Program (HAMQAP) was launched in collaboration with the National Institutes of Health (NIH) Office of Dietary Supplements (ODS) in 2017. HAMQAP was established to enable laboratories to improve the accuracy of measurements in samples that represent human intake (e.g., foods, dietary supplements, tobacco) and samples that represent human metabolism (e.g., blood, serum, plasma, urine) for demonstration of proficiency and/or compliance with various regulations. Analytes are paired where possible to represent the full spectrum of health assessment. Exercise 6 of this program offered the opportunity for laboratories to assess their in house measurements of nutritional elements (chlorine, iodine, chromium, molybdenum, and selenium), toxic elements (arsenic, cadmium, lead, and mercury), contaminants (chlorate and perchlorate, glyphosate and aminomethylphosphonic acid (AMPA)), water-soluble vitamins (biotin and vitamin C), fat-soluble vitamins (vitamins A and E), fatty acids (select omega-3 and omega-6 fatty acids), botanicals (anthocyanidins), natural products (caffeine, theobromine, and theophylline), and proximates (fat, protein, carbohydrates, solids, ash, and calories) in foods and dietary supplements, and corresponding biomarkers/metabolites in clinical specimens (human red blood cells).</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8394"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8394"/>
</reference>