<reference anchor="NIST.SP.800-160v2r1" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.800-160v2r1">
  <front>
    <title>Developing cyber-resilient systems :a systems security engineering approach</title>
    <author fullname="Ron Ross" initials="R." surname="Ross">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Victoria Pillitteri" initials="V." surname="Pillitteri">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Richard Graubart" initials="R." surname="Graubart">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Deborah Bodeau" initials="D." surname="Bodeau">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rosalie McQuaid" initials="R." surname="McQuaid">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="December" day="8"/>
    <abstract>NIST Special Publication (SP) 800-160, Volume 2, Revision 1, focuses on cyber resiliency engineering an emerging specialty systems engineering discipline applied in conjunction with systems security engineering and resilience engineering to develop survivable, trustworthy secure systems. Cyber resiliency engineering intends to architect, design, develop, implement, maintain, and sustain the trustworthiness of systems with the capability to anticipate, withstand, recover from, and adapt to adverse conditions, stresses, attacks, or compromises that use or are enabled by cyber resources. From a risk management perspective, cyber resiliency is intended to help reduce the mission, business, organizational, enterprise or sector risk of depending on cyber resources. This publication can be used in conjunction with ISO/IEC/IEEE 15288:2015, Systems and software engineering Systems life cycle processes, NIST Special Publication (SP) 800-160, Volume 1, Systems Security Engineering Considerations for a Multidisciplinary Approach in the Engineering of Trustworthy Secure Systems, NIST SP 800-37, Risk Management Framework for Information Systems and Organizations A System Life Cycle Approach for Security and Privacy; and NIST SP 800-53, Security and Privacy Controls for Information Systems and Organizations. It can be viewed as a handbook for achieving the identified cyber resiliency outcomes based on a systems engineering perspective on system life cycle and risk management processes, allowing the experience and expertise of the implementing organization to help determine how the content will be used for its purpose. Organizations can select, adapt, and use some or all of the cyber resiliency constructs (i.e., goals, objectives, techniques, approaches, and design principles) described in this publication and apply the constructs to the technical, operational, and threat environments for which systems need to be engineered.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.800-160v2r1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="800-160v2r1"/>
</reference>