<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1200-29" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1200-29">
  <front>
    <title>Preparation, characterization, and biological activity of stability-enhanced polyethyleneimine-conjugated gold nanoparticles (Au-PEI@NIST) for biological application</title>
    <author fullname="Tae Joon Cho" initials="T." surname="Cho">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vincent A Hackley" initials="V." surname="Hackley">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Feng Yi" initials="F." surname="Yi">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="David A LaVan" initials="D." surname="LaVan">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vytas Reipa" initials="V." surname="Reipa">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alessandro Tona" initials="A." surname="Tona">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bryant C Nelson" initials="B." surname="Nelson">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Christopher M Sims" initials="C." surname="Sims">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Natalia Farkas" initials="N." surname="Farkas">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="September" day="16"/>
    <abstract>In this special publication, we report on a modified synthetic process that results in a stable suspension of Au-PEI nanoparticles, Au-PEI@NIST. Synthesized materials were characterized using an orthogonal approach that included dynamic light scattering (DLS), UV-Vis absorbance (UV-Vis), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), atomic force microscope (AFM), and thermogravimetric analysis (TGA). Very importantly, the end-product in this study demonstrated excellent colloidal stability in multiple aqueous environments including over a wide pH and temperature range of physiological relevance. The product also exhibited long-term storage stability under ambient conditions. Furthermore, the cytotoxicity of Au-PEI@NIST was investigated using the CHO K1 cell line and exhibited dose proportional toxicity, which suggested potential for use as a positive control in nanotoxicology studies. The results and stringent testing regimen point toward an effective and sustainable approach that can serve as a clarified starting point for the development of more complex conjugates for nanomedicine area.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.1200-29"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="1200-29"/>
</reference>