<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8479" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8479">
  <front>
    <title>An infrastructure for curating, querying, and augmenting document data</title>
    <author fullname="Subrahmanian, Eswaran.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sousa Amaral, Guillaume.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bhat, Talapady N.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brady, Kevin G.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brady Mary C.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Collard, Jacob N.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chouder, Sarah.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dessauw, Philippe J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dima, Alden A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Elliott, John T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Keyrouz, Walid.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Long, Benjamin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sexton, Rachael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lelouche, Nicolas J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sriram, Ram D.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>With the advent of the COVID-19 pandemic, there was the hope that data science approaches could help discover means for understanding, mitigating, and treating the disease. This manifested itself in the creation of the COVID-19 Open Research Dataset (CORD-19) which aggregated COVID-19- related scientific literature for use by the data mining community. As a group of interdisciplinary informatics researchers at NIST, we embarked on an effort to use our experience and previously developed systems to explore whether we could enhance the CORD-19 data set and facilitate its use. This effort produced a prototype scientific informatics system that extended data curation, data repository, resource registry, term extraction and indexing systems and resulted in a repackaging of CORD-19 as a Python data package. This paper documents our efforts, provides lessons learned, and proposes a general architecture for these types of systems.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8479"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8479"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8479"/>
</reference>