<reference anchor="NIST.AMS.100-23" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.AMS.100-23">
  <front>
    <title>Summary report on the industry forum for monitoring, diagnostics, and prognostics for manufacturing operations</title>
    <author fullname="Weiss, Brian A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brundage, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tamm, Yannick.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Makila, Tommi.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pellegrino, Joan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) hosted the Industry Forum: Advanced Monitoring, Diagnostic, and Prognostic for Manufacturing Operations on May 8- 11, 2018, on the NIST Gaithersburg (Maryland) campus. The purpose of the Industry Forum was to discuss the current trends, successes, challenges, and needs related to advanced monitoring, diagnostic, and prognostic technologies (collectively known as Prognostics and Health Management (PHM)) for enhancing maintenance and control strategies within manufacturing operations. The conclusion of the event featured an American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) Standards meeting for the Advanced Monitoring, Diagnostics, and Prognostics for Manufacturing Operations Subcommittee1 to prioritize work activities for standards and guidelines. This report documents the four-day event, summarizing presentations and brainstorming sessions, in addition to detailing the key priority topics for standards and guidelines. The next steps in this effort are presented towards the end of this document, including planning for the next standards meeting (which has since occurred in October 2018 in Cincinnati, Ohio) and the 2019 Measurement and Evaluation for Prognostics and Health Management in Manufacturing Forum (ME4PHM) workshop.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.AMS.100-23"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST advanced manufacturing series; NIST AMS" value="100-23"/>
</reference>