<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8438" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8438">
  <front>
    <title>Twenty-Fifth Annual Report on Federal Agency Use of Voluntary Consensus Standards and Conformity Assessment</title>
    <author fullname="Nathalie Rioux" initials="N." surname="Rioux">
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022"/>
    <abstract>In FY 2021, the 22 federal agencies that reported did not add or rescind any GUS in lieu of VCS, therefore there remains a total of 80 previously reported GUS in lieu of VCS still in use. This analysis does not reflect the use of standards by the Department of Defense (DoD) or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) as they report their use of GUS on a categorical basis via a different reporting mechanism. Agencies demonstrate the effectiveness of the NTTAA and Circular A-119 by their continuous review of opportunities to rescind GUS in favor of using VCS, and their involvement with the private sector through the VCS process. These activities suggest that federal agencies are cognizant of the benefits of meeting their mission needs by actively seeking to use VCS developed by the private sector. In accordance with its coordination role as defined in the NTTAA and OMB A-119, NIST continues to assist federal agencies and their stakeholders with standards and conformity assessment information, program support, guidance, and policy concerns. NIST hosts http://standards.gov, which offers ongoing practical guidance and information needed by agencies to implement the NTTAA successfully and report standards activities as required by the NTTAA and OMB Circular A-119. This report fulfills the annual reporting requirements of both the NTTAA and OMB Circular A-119.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8438"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST NISTIRs (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8438"/>
</reference>