<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8243" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8243">
  <front>
    <title>A test method for measuring response robot performance under attenuated radio conditions</title>
    <author fullname="Kimble, Kenneth E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Candell, Richard.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Saidi, Kamel S.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Emergency and disaster situations are unavoidable. Earthquakes, severe weather, bomb threats, and war are an unfortunate reality. Firefighters, bomb technicians, and urban search and rescue specialists are the first to respond in emergency situations. These first responders risk their lives where remotely operated robots would be more suited for the dangers. Emergency response robots are designed for remote operation implying a wireless connection between the controller and robot. The performance of the wireless communication connection between controller and robot is typically non-ideal. Reflective and absorptive properties of the operational environment and interference degrade the communication system, limiting range, reliability, and timeliness. An affordable and effective method for evaluating the performance of emergency response robots under specific attenuated radio conditions is proposed in this paper. The method may be useful for continuing work on a current standard: E2855-12 Standard Test Method for Evaluating Emergency Response Robot Capabilities: Radio Communication: Non-Line-of-Sight Range[3] currently being pursued by the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) International Standards Committee on Homeland Security Applications.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8243"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8243"/>
</reference>