<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2095" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2095">
  <front>
    <title>A tool to model the Fate and Transport of Indoor Microbiological Aerosols (FaTIMA)</title>
    <author fullname="Dols, W. Stuart.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Polidoro, Brian J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Poppendieck, Dustin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Emmerich, Steven J. (Steven John)">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The web-based tool Fate and Transport of Indoor Microbiological Aerosols (FaTIMA) allows the determination of the fate of indoor microbiological aerosols associated with ventilation, filtration, deposition, and inactivation mechanisms. FaTIMA provides a representation of a single, well-mixed zone that is served by a mechanical ventilation system and incorporates source and removal mechanisms for an aerosol with a single, user-defined representative particle size. The simple mechanical ventilation system model allows specification of supply, return, and outdoor air intake rates to represent either a positive, negative or balanced ventilation system. Aerosol sources are provided to enable any combination of continuous, e.g., breathing-related emissions, or intermittent, e.g., coughing-related emissions. Aerosol removal mechanisms include filters within the ventilation system, room air cleaners, and deposition onto floors, walls, and ceilings. Simulations can be run for a 24-h period, with the results including the time history of the airborne concentration and surface loading, as well as integrated exposure of an occupant. Exposure is based on a uniform aerosol concentration within the zone and does not account for spatial differences in aerosol concentrations such as those due to momentum effects of respiratory emissions.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2095"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2095"/>
</reference>