<bibdata type="standard">
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Workshop Summary Report for “Building the Federal Profile for IoT Device Cybersecurity” Virtual Workshop</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Workshop Summary Report for “Building the Federal Profile for IoT Device Cybersecurity” Virtual Workshop</title>
  <uri type="doi">https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2021/NIST.IR.8322.pdf</uri>
  <docidentifier type="NIST">NISTIR 8322</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="DOI">10.6028/NIST.IR.8322</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2021-01</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <forename script="Latn">Katerina</forename>
        <surname script="Latn">Megas</surname>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <forename script="Latn">Michael</forename>
        <surname script="Latn">Fagan</surname>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <forename script="Latn">David</forename>
        <surname script="Latn">Lemire</surname>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>National Institute of Standards and Technology</name>
      <abbreviation>NIST</abbreviation>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language/>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" script="Latn">This report summarizes the feedback received on the work of the NIST Cybersecurity for IoT program on device cybersecurity at a virtual workshop in July 2020. NISTIR 8259, Foundational Cybersecurity Activities for IoT Device Manufacturers and NISTIR 8259A, IoT Device Cybersecurity Capability Core Baseline provide general guidance on how manufacturers can understand and approach their role in supporting customers’ cybersecurity needs and goals. As discussed in those documents, specific sectors and use cases may require more specific guidance than what is included in NISTIR 8259A’s core baseline for IoT devices. NIST conducted the virtual workshop “Building the Federal Profile for IoT Device Cybersecurity” to discuss and gather community input on the creation of a federal profile of the core baseline for use by federal agencies. This publication provides a summary of the workshop. The baseline will be published in NISTIR 8259D, Profile of the IoT Core Baseline for the Federal Government.</abstract>
  <place>Gaithersburg, MD</place>
  <ext>
    <doctype>standard</doctype>
  </ext>
</bibdata>