<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8370" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8370">
  <front>
    <title>The San Francisco Estuary Institute Collection at the NIST Biorepository</title>
    <author fullname="Debra Ellisor" initials="D." surname="Ellisor">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nina Buzby" initials="N." surname="Buzby">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Michael Weaver" initials="M." surname="Weaver">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Melissa Foley" initials="M." surname="Foley">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rebecca Pugh" initials="R." surname="Pugh">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="April" day="28"/>
    <abstract>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has been collaborating with the San Francisco Estuary Institute (SFEI) since 2009, providing biobanking services at the NIST Biorepository in Charleston, South Carolina, in support of their ongoing water quality monitoring program, the Regional Monitoring Program for Water Quality in the San Francisco Bay (RMP). Specimens (bivalve tissue, bird egg contents, fish tissue and sediment) are collected and processed by SFEI-partnering institutions according to their established protocols and shipped to the NIST Biorepository for archiving. This report outlines NIST s role in the project, describes collection and processing protocols developed by SFEI and their collaborators, details shipping and archival procedures employed by biorepository staff and provides an inventory of the collection maintained by NIST from 2009 to 2020.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8370"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8370"/>
</reference>