<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1800-7" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1800-7">
  <front>
    <title>Situational awareness for electric utilities</title>
    <author fullname="McCarthy, Jim.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alexander, Otis.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Crouse, Sarah Edwards,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Faatz, Don.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Peloquin, Chris.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Symington, Susan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thibault, André.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wiltberger, John.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Viani, Karen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Situational awareness, in the context of this guide, is the understanding of one's environment and the ability to predict how it might change due to various factors. As part of their current cybersecurity efforts, some electric utilities monitor physical, operational, and information technology (IT) separately. According to energy sector stakeholders, many utilities are currently assessing a more comprehensive approach to situational awareness, which, through increased real-time or near real-time cybersecurity monitoring, can enhance the resilience of their operations. The National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence (NCCoE) at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) built a laboratory environment to explore an example solution that can be used by energy sector companies to alert their staff to potential or actual cyber attacks directed at the grid. The security characteristics in our situational awareness platform are informed by guidance and best practices from standards organizations, including the NIST Cybersecurity Framework and North American Electric Reliability Corporation's (NERC) Critical Infrastructure Protection (CIP) Version 5 standards. This NIST Cybersecurity Practice Guide demonstrates how organizations can use commercially available products that can be integrated with an organization's existing infrastructure. The combination of these products provides a converged view of all sensor data within the utility's network systems, including IT, operational, cyber, and physical access control systems, which often exists in separate 'silos.' The example solution is packaged as a 'how to' guide that demonstrates implementation of standardsbased cybersecurity technologies in the real world and based on risk management. The guide may help inform electric utilities in their efforts to gain situational awareness efficiencies. Doing so may enable faster monitoring, identification, and response to incidents while also saving research and proof-ofconcept costs for the sector and its ratepayers and customers.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1800-7"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1800-7"/>
</reference>