<reference anchor="NIST.GCR.21-028" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.GCR.21-028">
  <front>
    <title>Prospective economic impacts of allowing government-operated federal laboratories to assert copyright protection for their custom software products</title>
    <author fullname="David Leech" initials="P" surname="Leech">
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Scott" initials="T" surname="Scott">
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="May" day="1"/>
    <abstract>U.S. copyright laws do not allow government-owned government-operated (GOGO) laboratories of Federal agencies to obtain copyright protection for the software products they develop. This report provides an assessment of the likely economic effects of allowing copyright protection for software products created in the GOGO laboratories. The report uses a formal survey of Federal agencies GOGO laboratories and government-owned contractor-operated (GOCO) laboratories to describe their software development and licensing activities over the past five years and to make forecasts about the effects of eliminating the copyright prohibition. The survey responses indicate that if copyrights for government-created software are allowed, the availability of the software for use by others will increase dramatically. Forecasts of the economic impacts of the expected increase in the available software are made using estimated models of licensing revenues and licensing costs for the survey respondents. The forecasts for the respondents are extrapolated to their parent Federal agencies and then to all Federal agencies. Information about the economy-wide impact for the software industry is combined with the information about the software activities of the Federal agencies to project economy-wide benefits of lifting the restrictions on copyrighting software developed by GOGO laboratories. Changing the copyright law to allow copyright protection for GOGO software is expected to have a positive economic impact on the U.S. economy because the software made available will increase the productivity of its users. This report provides a first look at software activity that has not previously been systematically tracked and reported.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.GCR.21-028"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Grant/Contractor Reports" value="21-028"/>
</reference>