<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8452" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8452">
  <front>
    <title>Cannabis Laboratory Quality Assurance Program :exercise 2 toxic elements final report</title>
    <author fullname="Charles A Barber" initials="C." surname="Barber">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Colleen E Bryan Sallee" initials="C." surname="Sallee">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carolyn Q Burdette" initials="C." surname="Burdette">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shaun P Kotoski" initials="S." surname="Kotoski">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Melissa M Phillips" initials="M." surname="Phillips">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Walter B Wilson" initials="W." surname="Wilson">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laura J Wood" initials="L." surname="Wood">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="December" day="15"/>
    <abstract>In 2020, NIST launched CannaQAP to improve the comparability of the analytical measurements of cannabis and cannabis-derived products in forensic and cannabis (hemp and marijuana) testing laboratories. CannaQAP is an interlaboratory study mechanism that is similar to a proficiency testing scheme; however, the focus is towards education without assigning pass/fail grades to the anonymized participants. CannaQAP helps inform NIST about the current measurement capabilities of, and challenges faced by the analytical cannabis community. This in turn assists NIST in the design and characterization of cannabis reference materials (RMs). This study of CannaQAP Exercise 2 focused on the determination of toxic elements in two hemp materials and a control material provided by NIST. Arsenic, cadmium, lead, mercury, beryllium, cobalt, chromium, manganese, molybdenum, nickel, selenium, uranium, and vanadium were the toxic elements chosen based on interest expressed by the cannabis community. This report provides a detailed description of the results of this study.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8452"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST NISTIRs (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8452"/>
</reference>