<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1209" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1209">
  <front>
    <title>Summary of NIST/SIM chemical metrology working group training opportunity: isotope dilution-mass spectrometry clinical measurement course</title>
    <author fullname="Pritchett, Jeanita.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lippa, Katrice A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bedner, Mary.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Burdette, Carolyn Q.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Camara, Johanna E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Duewer, David L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lang, Brian E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nelson, Michael A.,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Possolo, Antonio.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brown Thomas, Jeanice.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sander, Lane C. (Lane Charles)">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sniegoski, Lorna T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tai, Susan S.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The one week NIST-SIM chemical metrology training opportunity was designed to provide SIM NMI/DI laboratory personnel with in-depth classroom and hands-on laboratory experience for the implementation of isotope dilution/mass spectrometry (ID/MS) methods in the application of clinical marker (cholesterol, glucose, and creatinine) measurements. A total of six NMI/DIs expressed an initial interest in this training course, and include the Instituto Nacional de Tecnologia Industrial (INTI) o Argentina, Instituto Nacional de Metrologia, Qualidade e Tecnologia (INMETRO) o Brazil, Instituto de Salud Publica (ISP) o Chile, Instituto Nacional de Metrologia de Colombia (INM (CO)) o Colombia, Centro Nacional de Metrologia (CENAM) o Mexico, and Laboratorio Tecnologico del Uruguay (LATU) o Uruguay, Instituto Nacional Decalidad (INACAL)-Peru. The course was offered by the Chemical Sciences Division at NIST in Gaithersburg, MD July 18-22, 2016.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1209"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1209"/>
</reference>