<reference anchor="NIST.AMS.200-11" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.AMS.200-11">
  <front>
    <title>Guide for environmentally sustainable investment analysis based on ASTM E3200</title>
    <author fullname="Douglas Thomas" initials="D." surname="Thomas">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Anand Kandaswamy" initials="M" surname="Kandaswamy">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="David Butry" initials="D." surname="Butry">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="March" day="15"/>
    <abstract>This guide presents techniques for evaluating manufacturing investments from the perspective of environmentally sustainable manufacturing by pairing economic methods of investment analysis with environmental aspect of manufacturing, including manufacturing processes. The methods are based on ASTM E3200 and, although the focus is on manufacturing, they can be applied under other circumstances (e.g., construction industry investments, agriculture, or mining). The economic techniques include net present value, internal rate of return, payback period, and hurdle rate. The guide also includes sensitivity analyses with a focus on Monte Carlo techniques. The methods presented can be used by manufacturers, regardless of size or complexity, to make environmentally sustainable decisions, including but not limited to whether to embark on an investment, discontinue a manufacturing line, invest or re-invest in a new project or factory.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.AMS.200-11"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Advanced Manufacturing Series" value="200-11"/>
</reference>