<reference anchor="NIST.IR.7082e2018" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.7082-2018">
  <front>
    <title>Proficiency test policy and plan for state weights &amp; measures laboratories (2018 ed)</title>
    <author fullname="Harris, Georgia L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Eason, L. F.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fraley, Ken.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Larson, Kelleen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Physical Measurement Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.))</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This publication provides the policies and plans for the PT Program of the NIST Office of Weights and Measures. This Office of Weights and Measures (OWM) Proficiency Testing (PT) policy and plan has been updated to ensure compliance with the latest applicable documentary standards and policies of the International Laboratory Accreditation Cooperation (ILAC). The PT program has been in place since the early 1980s as a core part of the support to State weights and measures laboratories through regional measurement assurance programs. Original activities were conducted as round robins in support of ongoing measurement assurance activities related to support for State laws with requirements for metrological traceability to national and international standards. Kelleen Larson, L. F. Eason, and Ken Fraley in collaboration with NIST OWM personnel at the 2012 PT Workshop, Boulder, Colorado, proposed significant updates to this publication, which form the foundation for the 2018 update. Reviews by the participants listed below significantly contributed to the development of this policy and plan. The initial 2004 edition was developed under contract with Jeff C. Gust.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.7082-2018"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="7082-2018"/>
</reference>