<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8237" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8237">
  <front>
    <title>Health assessment measurements quality assurance program</title>
    <author fullname="Barber, Charles A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Benner, Jr., Bruce A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brown Thomas, Jeanice.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Burdette, Carolyn Q.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Camara, Johanna.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Long, Stephen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Murray, Jacolin A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Phillips, Melissa M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Place, Benjamin J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rimmer, Catherine A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wood, Laura J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yu, Lee.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chinthalapati, Siva K.R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tai, Susan S.-C.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The NIST Health Assessment Measurements Quality Assurance Program (HAMQAP) was launched in collaboration with the National Institutes of Health (NIH) Office of Dietary Supplements (ODS) in 2017. HAMQAP was established to enable laboratories to improve the accuracy of measurements for demonstration of compliance with various regulations by measuring samples that represent human intake (e.g., foods, dietary supplements, tobacco) and samples that represent human output (e.g., blood, serum, plasma, urine). Analytes are paired where possible to represent the full spectrum of health assessment. Exercise 1 of this program offered the opportunity for laboratories to assess their in-house measurements of nutritional elements (iron and transferrin), contaminants (arsenic species and mycotoxins), water-soluble vitamins (vitamin B12), fat-soluble vitamins (vitamin D and metabolites), fatty acids, and botanical marker compounds (actein and 27-deoxyactein) in foods, botanical or dietary supplement ingredients, and human serum, plasma, or urine.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8237"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8237"/>
</reference>