<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2153" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2153">
  <front>
    <title>Ignitibility of structural wood products exposed to embers during wildland fires :a review of literature</title>
    <author fullname="Shonali Nazare" initials="S." surname="Nazare">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Isaac Leventon" initials="I." surname="Leventon">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rick Davis" initials="R." surname="Davis">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="April" day="27"/>
    <abstract>Ignitability of structural components due to ember accumulation is a common cause of structural fires in wildland urban interface (WUI) communities. To fire harden structures in WUI communities, it is important to quantitatively predict the ember ignitability of wooden substrates. To commence this effort, past studies have been compiled and analyzed to identify knowledge gaps. Key topics including ignition of structures in WUI fires, measurement of thermal response of solid wood products used in residential structures, controlling mechanisms in ignition and sustained smoldering of wood, measurement of ember properties, real-scale and bench-scale experiments on assessing ember ignitability of structural components, and surrogate ignition sources for assessing smoldering propensity of the wooden substrate have been reviewed. Existing test methods have also been reviewed in the light of common exposures seen WUI environment.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.TN.2153"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Technical Notes" value="2153"/>
</reference>