<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8388" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8388">
  <front>
    <title>Verifying executability of SysML behavior models using Alloy Analyzer</title>
    <author fullname="Jeremy Doerr" initials="J." surname="Doerr">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Conrad Bock" initials="C." surname="Bock">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Raphael Barbau" initials="R." surname="Barbau">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="August" day="24"/>
    <abstract>This report presents an approach to verifying executability of system behavior models by treating them as logical constraint problems solved using Alloy Analyzer, a non-proprietary software tool supporting a textual language for logical constraints and underlying solvers. With behavior models interpreted as constraints on execution order, Alloy can determine whether the models are executable by attempting to find executions that meet those constraints. The approach relies on a logical interpretation of behavior modeling in the Systems Modeling Language (SysML) by Ontological Behavior Modeling method that unifies SysML behavior modeling based on its classification elements. This paper proposes translation between logical versions of SysML behavioral models and logical constructs in Alloy. Finally, the approach is demonstrated by translating and solving example SysML behavior models.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8388"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8388"/>
</reference>