<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1218" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1218">
  <front>
    <title>Road mapping workshop report on overcoming barriers to adoption of composites in sustainable infrastructure</title>
    <author fullname="Sheridan, Richard Brinsley,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gilman, Jeffrey W.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Busel, John P.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hartman, Dave.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Holmes, Gale.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Coughlin, Dan (Daniel)">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kelley, Paul.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="O'Donnell, William R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nanni, Antonio.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Troutman, Dustin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Harris, Robert W.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gutierrez, Jim.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bakis, Charles.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Holmes, Scott.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Moser, Robert.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lackey, Ellen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fekete, Jim.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Watson, Stephanie.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kim, Jae-Hyun.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Forster, Aaron.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Krishnamurthy, Ajay.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Natarajan, Bharath.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The February 2017 Road Mapping Workshop on Overcoming Barriers to Adoption of Composites in Infrastructure brought together designers, manufacturers, researchers, and end-users to identify barriers and potential solutions. Composite products produced in the US offer durable, sustainable, and cost-effective solutions in a variety of infrastructure applications as diverse as dams, levees, bridges, highways, railroads, harbors, utility poles, and buildings. The overall goal of the workshop was to enable the adoption of world-leading US composite technology, thereby saving construction costs, and creating a durable 21st century infrastructure that supports economic growth. The workshop was a seminal event; it was the first time that such a complete cross section of interests was assembled to address the specific issue of enabling composites adoption in infrastructure. The meeting identified three activities (Durability Testing, Design Data Clearinghouse, and Training and Education) that, if enacted, will facilitate wider adoption of technology that is more reliable, durable, and cost effective. The workshop resulted in a roadmap for addressing barriers to the adoption of composites in infrastructure.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1218"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1218"/>
</reference>