<reference anchor="NIST.IR.7708" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.7708">
  <front>
    <title>Marine Environmental Specimen Bank</title>
    <author fullname="Moors, Amanda J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pugh, Rebecca S.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rust, Lauren B.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Porter, Barbara J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kimbrough, Kimani L.,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lauenstein, Gunnar G.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Becker, Paul R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wise, Stephen A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The National Status and Trends (NS) Program, was initiated in 1984 by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to address concerns about the condition of the Nation's coastal and estuarine ecosystems1,2. This Program consists of the National Benthic Surveillance (established in 1984) and Mussel Watch, one of the longest (inaugural year, 1986) nation-wide continuous contaminant monitoring programs in U.S. coastal waters3. The goal of the NS Program is to quantify current status and long-term trends in concentrations of selected contaminants in biological indicator organisms and environmental matrices of coastal and estuarine areas in the U.S.2 In the initial years of the Program, benthic fish, shellfish, sediment, and bivalve tissue were collected on a regular basis for real-time chemical analysis from sites along the U.S. In addition to real-time analysis and monitoring of these materials, the Program collects samples of mussels and oysters for long-term banking and future retrospective analyses. Due to a decrease in funding, specimen banking for the Program ended in 1992; however specimen banking for the Mussel Watch portion resumed in 20054. Each collection year, approximately 10% of the samples that are collected from Mussel Watch sites are archived at one of two specimen bank facilities operated by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)5: the National Biomonitoring Specimen Bank (NBSB), established in 1987, located on the main NIST campus in Gaithersburg, Maryland, and the Marine Environmental Specimen Bank (Marine ESB), established in 1998, located at the Hollings Marine Laboratory in Charleston, South Carolina. This report describes the program history, and the detailed collection, processing, and long-term storage protocols practiced by NIST's Environmental Specimen Banking System for Mussel Watch.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.7708"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="7708"/>
</reference>