<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2097" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2097">
  <front>
    <title>Analysis of iris images from Twins Day</title>
    <author fullname="Matey, James R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Grother, Patrick J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Quinn, George W.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Each year since 1976, the town of Twinsburg, Ohio has held a Twins Days Festival. Over the past 43 years over 77,000 sets of twins and multiples have attended ⁰₃ with many repeat visits over the years. Prof. Jeremy Dawson and other staff from the West Virginia University Biometrics Collection Lab have engaged with the Twins Days organizers since 2010 to collect biometric data from twins attending the festivals; the collections were carried out under Institutional Review Board (IRB) protocols and with informed consent of the individuals participating. NIST recently obtained copies of the Twins Day data for use in ongoing evaluations of face, finger and iris recognition algorithms. This paper is an initial analysis of the iris images taken at the 2010 festival. We see no evidence that the non-mated distribution for identical twin pairs is significantly different from that for unrelated individuals for two commercial iris recognition algorithms. This is not a surprise; Daugman demonstrated, using iris2pi, that a non-mated distribution of match scores from genetically identical left/right pairs from the same individual is not significantly different from that for pairs from different individuals and recently demonstrated results on twins similar to what we found. Analysis of iris images from subsequent festivals as well as face and finger images are planned.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2097"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2097"/>
</reference>