<reference anchor="NIST.MONO.1-9" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.MONO.1-9">
  <front>
    <title>Structural fire response and probable collapse sequence of World Trade Center Building 7</title>
    <author fullname="McAllister, Therese.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gann, Richard G.,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Averill, Jason D.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gross, John L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Grosshandler, William Lytle.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lawson, J. R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McGrattan, Kevin B.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pitts, William M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Prasad, Kuldeep R.,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sadek, Fahim H.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This report provides technical documentation of how NIST reconstructed the effects of the events on September 11, 2001 on WTC 7. This includes how the fires that followed the impact of debris from the collapse of WTC 1 (the north tower) led to the collapse of WTC 7; an evaluation of the building evacuation and emergency response procedures; what procedures and practices were used in the design, construction, operation, and maintenance of the building; and areas in current building and fire codes, standards, and practices that warrant revision. This report also describes how NIST reached its conclusions. NIST complemented in-house expertise with private sector technical experts; accumulated copious documents, photographs, and videos of the disaster; conducted first-person interviews of building occupants and emergency responders; analyzed the evacuation and emergency response operations in and around WTC 7; performed computer simulations of the behavior of WTC 7 on September 11, 2001; and combined the knowledge gained into a probable collapse sequence.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.MONO.1-9"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST NCSTAR; National Construction Safety Team Act report" value="1-9"/>
</reference>