<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8407" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8407">
  <front>
    <title>Experiments to test the A-UGV capabilities standard</title>
    <author fullname="Soocheol Yoon" initials="S." surname="Yoon">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Roger Bostelman" initials="R." surname="Bostelman">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ann Virts" initials="A." surname="Virts">
      <organization>Engineering Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="December" day="8"/>
    <abstract>Automatic, Automated, or Autonomous - Unmanned Ground Vehicles (A-UGVs), as referred to by ASTM International Committee F45, are industrial vehicles that have capabilities to navigate, dock, avoid obstacles, and interact with other vehicles and systems all within intended environments (e.g., warehouses, hospitals, outdoor facility perimeters) set by the manufacturer. A new ASTM F45 standard is near the ballot stage to serve as a guide for providing a basis for A-UGV manufacturers and users to compare capabilities between A-UGVs. The guide includes a report for documenting that the user has proven or asserted a capability, not tested the capability, or that the A-UGV does not have the capability. Although an infinite number of A-UGV tests are possible, this paper provides three cases that test the new standard where one case demonstrated in a complex dual-vehicles test, several capabilities as written in the standard. Alternatively, two cases demonstrated through experiments that A-UGV capabilities as written in the standard may need improvements and as such, the paper provides recommendations for modifying the standard.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8407"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST NISTIRs (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8407"/>
</reference>