<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8215" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8215">
  <front>
    <title>Forensic latent fingerprint preprocessing assessment</title>
    <author fullname="Lee, Paul.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Guan, Haiying.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dienstfrey, Andrew.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Theofanos, Mary.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stanton, Brian.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Schwarz, Matthew T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Latent fingerprints are made visible from the surface of objects using a variety of methods including physical and chemical processing, adapted illumination sources, and photographs. Unfortunately, the prints collected directly from a crime scene or from physical evidence may be incomplete or damaged, to the point of being considered unsuitable to send directly to latent fingerprint examiners for identification or to Automated Fingerprint Identification System (AFIS) for recognition. As a result, most latent fingerprint images must be preprocessed to enhance fingerprint information, at the same time suppressing interference arising from noise and otherwise unwanted image features. This preprocessing phase occurs after the latent print is collected from the crime scene and digitalized by a scanner or camera, and before the image analysis and process phase such as minutiae markup or latent print identification. The preprocessing results can be extraordinary, transforming raw images with little or no value into ones suitable for evidentiary analysis. Despite the importance of this step, there exist few databases designed especially for the scientific study of latent fingerprint image preprocessing, and even fewer standards to guide this workflow. To address this research gap, we conducted a study in which a group of trained Latent Print Examiners provided Extended Feature Set (EFS) markups of a series of latent images. This report provides a brief introduction into fingerprint preprocessing, discussion regarding the experimental design, structure, and contents of the latent fingerprint image database, and details of proposed preprocessing efficacy metrics. Additionally, we present preliminary analysis of these metrics when applied to images in our database. Previously Guan et al. [6] presented the performance metrics and analysis of the metrics as applied to a union minutiae set. In this report, we comprehensively document the contents of the records database including the latent images, the EFS markup files, metadata, markup logs, and region of interest masks. Additionally, we present the results of the performance metrics as applied to the intersection minutiae set of EFS markup data.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8215"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8215"/>
</reference>