<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8277" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8277">
  <front>
    <title>Voices of first responders - examining public safety communication from the rural perspective</title>
    <author fullname="Greene, Kristen K.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dawkins, Shane¿̐¿.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Theofanos, Mary F.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Steves, Michelle.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Furman, Susanne.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Choong, Yee-Yin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Prettyman, Sandra Spickard,">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>With the newly created Nationwide Public Safety Broadband Network (NPSBN), the public safety community has a unique opportunity to review and improve communication technology for first responders, in urban, suburban, and rural areas. Understanding the problems and challenges currently experienced by first responders provides the basis for addressing and developing solutions to improve public safety communication. The National Institute of Standards and Technology Public Safety Communications Research (PSCR) usability team conducted in-depth interviews with approximately 200 first responders representing 13 states in eight Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) regions across the United States. From this larger dataset, this Volume 3 report focuses on the contexts and challenges specifically faced by rural first responders. This Volume utilizes 48 interviews with 63 rural first responders. A qualitative analysis of the transcribed interview data revealed unique issues posed by rural geography and topography; incident types specific to the rural environment; and resource challenges faced by rural first responder departments and agencies. Resource challenges include financial, personnel, and infrastructure. While there are many similarities between rural first responders and their urban and suburban counterparts, this Volume focuses on the unique nature of rural emergency response and its implications for technology needs and development. Understanding the specific challenges faced by first responders in rural communities can provide insight into the types of technology that might help them best respond to incidents effectively, efficiently, and safely.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8277"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8277"/>
</reference>