<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2272" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2272">
  <front>
    <title>Application of the Hybrid Satellite Network cybersecurity framework profile</title>
    <author fullname="Byers, Frederick.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mamula, Dan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Meldorf, Karri.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brule, Joseph.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jennings, Rory.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wiltberger, John.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Craft, Eugene.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dombrowski, John.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lattin, O’Ryan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Noor, Abdul.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yetto, Matt.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mamonau, Aliaksander.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Slivina, Oksana.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sharma, Jay.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zheng, Kangmin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The space sector is transitioning towards Hybrid Satellite Networks (HSN), an aggregation of independently owned and operated terminals, antennas, satellites, payloads, or other components that comprise a satellite system. The elements of an HSN may have varying levels of assurance. HSNs may interact with government systems and critical infrastructure (as defined by the Department of Homeland Security). A framework is required to assess the security posture of the individual components while still enabling the HSN to provide its function. This report applies the NIST Cybersecurity Framework to HSNs with an emphasis on the interfaces between the participants of the HSN. HSNs have different cybersecurity concerns relative to a more traditional vertically integrated space system. This technical note presents a representative fictious scenario to demonstrate how to apply the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Internal Report (IR) 8441 Cybersecurity Framework (CSF) Profile to a notional HSN.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.TN.2272"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2272"/>
</reference>