<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8084e2023" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8084e2023">
  <front>
    <title>The NIST plan for providing public access to results of federally funded research</title>
    <author fullname="Sharpless, Katherine E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Avila, Regina.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Boisvert, Ronald.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dohne, A. Kirk.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fowler, James.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Glenn, Rachel B.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greene, Gretchen R.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hanisch, Robert.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Medina-Smith, Andrea.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Munter, Alan E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Petrousky, Julie.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ralchenko, Yuri.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rowland, Carolyn D.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="St. Pierre, James A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wunderlich, Adam.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhang, Jon.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>In 2013 White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) issued a memo, “Increasing Access to the Results of Federally Funded Scientific Research.” In response, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) developed a public access plan and published a compilation of input received when the plan was posted for comment. NIST policy and associated directives were developed from the plan, and NIST has been operating under that policy since 2015.In 2022, OSTP issued another memo, “Ensuring Immediate, Free, and Equitable Access to Federally Funded Research.” NIST has expanded the original plan to include requirements of this new memo. The plan was posted for public comment, with the comment period ending on August 14, 2023. This document is a collection of the plan, the Federal Register Notice, and comments received. Comments will inform the policy and associated directives that are being developed from the revised plan.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8084e2023"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8084e2023"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8084e2023"/>
</reference>