<reference anchor="NIST.TN.1973" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.1973">
  <front>
    <title>A methodology for estimating seismic retrofit costs</title>
    <author fullname="Fung, Juan F.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Butry, David T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sattar, Siamak.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McCabe, S. L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Presidential Executive Order 13717 (EO 13717), Establishing a Federal Earthquake Risk Management Standard, encourages federal agencies to enhance resilience...[to] future earthquakes by evaluating and retrofitting existing federal buildings based on current existing building codes. However, while guidance on evaluation and retrofit practices is readily available, a standard approach to estimating retrofit costs does not exist. Moreover, the absence of easily obtainable estimates can make retrofits prohibitive for decision-makers. This paper develops a cost-estimating methodology for seismic retrofits that (1) captures the essential factors that drive seismic retrofit costs, such as building construction and square footage; and (2) is reproducible using data available to decision-makers. The methodology builds on FEMA 156 and 157, Typical Costs for Seismic Rehabilitation of Existing Buildings, Volumes 1 and 2. A series of regression models is fit to the data used for the FEMA reports, with the models varying in the level of data required; e.g., a decision-maker may not have information on building construction for each asset in their inventory. Thus, the trade-off from estimating retrofit costs subject to data limitations can be quantified in terms of prediction error, providing decision-makers with a set of options for estimating costs together with a measure of predictive performance. We find that a simple model, in terms of data requirements, can deliver reliable predictions.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.1973"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="1973"/>
</reference>