<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1500-18" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-18">
  <front>
    <title>Research Data Framework (RDaF) :
motivation, development, and a preliminary framework core</title>
    <author fullname="Robert Hanisch" initials="J" surname="Hanisch">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Debra Kaiser" initials="L" surname="Kaiser">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bonnie Carroll" initials="C" surname="Carroll">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="February" day="21"/>
    <abstract>NIST is leading the development of the Research Data Framework (RDaF) with involvement and input from national and international leaders in the broad research data stakeholder community. Research data is defined here as the recorded factual material commonly accepted in the scientific community as necessary to validate research findings. The overarching goal of the RDaF is to provide the stakeholder community with a structured approach to develop a customizable strategy for the management of research data. The audience for the RDaF is the entire research data community, including all organizations and individuals engaged in any activities concerned with research data management, from Chief Executive Officers and Chief Data Officers to librarians and researchers. This document describes the motivation for, and the development of, a Preliminary Framework Core, and identifies the next steps in further development of the RDaF. The research data environment is rapidly changing, and this Framework shall remain a living document. Revisions will be made as we, the stakeholders of the RDaF, gain experience with its application and use.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-18"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="1500-18"/>
</reference>