<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8484" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8484">
  <front>
    <title>Safeguarding international science</title>
    <author fullname="Strouse, Gregory F.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Saundry, Claire M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wood, Timothy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bennett, Philip A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bedner, Mary.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The U.S. science and research ecosystem retains its leadership by actively engaging with the global community through the conduct of mutually beneficial collaborative research and the welcoming of international scientists. Coupled with that, the national and economic security of the United States depends on effective risk management practices for organizations that engage in international collaborative research to protect against undue foreign influence and interference. The National Institute of Standards of Technology (NIST) Safeguarding Science Research Security Framework (“Framework”) establishes guidance to assist the U.S. science and research community [e.g., U.S. Government (USG), academia, and industry] across the broad spectrum of international science and technology activities as well as Federal funding initiatives. This Framework is designed to enable organizations to implement a mission-focused, integrated, risk-balanced program through the application of research security principles and best practices that fosters the safeguarding of international science while mitigating risks to the integrity of the open collaborative environment. This Framework is a living document and will continue to be updated and improved as its users provide feedback on implementation of review procedures or to address new or emerging risks. This will ensure it is meeting the needs of Research Security practitioners in a dynamic and challenging environment of new threats, risks, and creative solutions.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8484"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8484"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8484"/>
</reference>