<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8343" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8343">
  <front>
    <title>Health assessment measurements quality assurance program</title>
    <author fullname="Barber, Chuck.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Burdette, Carolyn.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hayes, Hugh.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luvonga, Caleb.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Phillips, Melissa M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rimmer, Kate.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wood, Laura J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yu, Lee L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>HAMQAP was launched in collaboration with the NIH Office of Dietary Supplements (ODS) in 2017. HAMQAP was established to enable laboratories to improve the accuracy of measurements in samples that represent human intake (e.g., foods, dietary supplements, tobacco) and samples that represent human metabolism (e.g., blood, serum, plasma, urine) for demonstration of proficiency and/or compliance with various regulations. Analytes are paired where possible to represent the full spectrum of health assessment. Exercise 5 of this program offered the opportunity for laboratories to assess their in house measurements of nutritional elements (calcium, iron, potassium, and sodium), contaminants (arsenic and arsenic species, chlorate and perchlorate), water-soluble vitamins (several B vitamins), fat-soluble vitamins (vitamin D and metabolites), fatty acids (select omega-3 and omega-6 fatty acids), botanicals (catechins), natural products (xanthines), and proximates in foods and dietary supplements, and corresponding biomarkers/metabolites in clinical specimens (human red blood cells, sera, and urine).</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8343"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8343"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8343"/>
</reference>