<reference anchor="NIST.SP.260-220" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.260-220">
  <front>
    <title>Certification of Standard Reference Material 3289 multivitamin tablets</title>
    <author fullname="Hugh V Hayes" initials="H." surname="Hayes">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jerome Mulloor" initials="J." surname="Mulloor">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Michael A Nelson" initials="M." surname="Nelson">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Catherine A Rimmer" initials="C." surname="Rimmer">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laura Regalado" initials="L." surname="Regalado">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="James H Yen" initials="J." surname="Yen">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lee L Yu" initials="L." surname="Yu">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="March" day="18"/>
    <abstract>Standard Reference Material (SRM ) 3289 Multivitamin Tablets was developed as part of a collaborative effort between the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) and the National Institutes of Health Office of Dietary Supplements (NIH ODS) as a partial replacement for SRM 3280 Multivitamin/Multielement Tablets. SRM 3289 was formulated with both vitamins and elements to replicate all analytical challenges associated with the measurement of vitamins in dietary supplement matrices. The material was purchased pre-packaged from Gemini Pharmaceuticals (Commack, NY), an experienced contract manufacturer. Certified values for fat-soluble and water-soluble vitamin-related measurands have been assigned based upon data obtained from NIST, manufacturer, and interlaboratory comparison measurements. A description of the material, sample preparations, results, and data analysis are discussed in the following report.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.260-220"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="260-220"/>
</reference>