<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8449" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8449">
  <front>
    <title>Cannabis Laboratory Quality Assurance Program</title>
    <author fullname="Barber, Charles A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sallee, Colleen E. Bryan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Burdette, Carolyn Q.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kotoski, Shaun P.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Phillips, Melissa M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wilson, Walter B.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wood, Laura J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>In 2020, NIST launched Cannabis Laboratory Quality Assurance Program (CannaQAP) to improve the comparability of the analytical measurements of cannabis and cannabis-derived products in forensic and cannabis (hemp and marijuana) testing laboratories. CannaQAP is an interlaboratory study mechanism that is similar to a proficiency testing scheme; however, the focus is towards education without assigning pass/fail grades to the anonymized participants. CannaQAP helps inform NIST about the current measurement capabilities of, and challenges faced by the analytical cannabis community. This in turn assists NIST in the design and characterization of cannabis reference materials (RMs). This study of Exercise 2 of CannaQAP focused on the determination of moisture in one hemp material provided by NIST. This report provides a detailed description of the results of this study. The wide range of moisture loss reported by participating laboratories using several different drying methods indicates the need for consistent hemp drying method(s) for accurate and precise measurements.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8449"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8449"/>
</reference>