<reference anchor="NIST.VTS.100-3pt2" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-3pt2">
  <front>
    <title>Usability and accessibility of electronic pollbooks</title>
    <author fullname="Quesenbery, Whitney.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Baumeister, Lynn.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dawkins, Shanée.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This document is the second part of a series of documents on the usability of electronic pollbooks. It contains a procedure for how e-pollbooks might be evaluated, including a preliminary protocol for running a usability test. It can be used by people designing or purchasing an e-pollbook, as a usability component for a certification or approval process, or to determine aspects of the product that need special attention in training poll workers. This usability testing procedure puts an e-pollbook through its paces, allowing discovery of potential usability issues before an election. Seeing how people who might be poll workers interact with the e-pollbook goes beyond the feature checklist and provides a sense for how easy, or hard, it is for poll workers to use the e-pollbook to do their jobs on Election Day. Research referenced in this report was conducted in 2017. The use of e-pollbooks presented throughout the document reflects the state of elections in 2017. In the time since this research was performed, e-pollbooks have made progress addressing usability and accessibility issues. Additionally, as part of its ongoing Election Supporting Technology Evaluation Program (ESTEP) program, the Election Assistance Commission developed the Voluntary Electronic Poll Book Requirements (VEPBR) in collaboration with NIST. This publication is intended to provide a deep dive into how to evaluate the usability and accessibility of e-pollbooks in order to meet the relevant VEPBR user-centered design process and usability testing requirements as well as any state certifications pertaining to usability and accessibility.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-3pt2"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST voting technology standard; NIST VTS" value="100-3pt2"/>
</reference>