<reference anchor="NIST.GCR.20-025" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.GCR.20-025">
  <front>
    <title>Federal agency return on investment in foreign patenting</title>
    <author fullname="David P Leech" initials="D." surname="Leech">
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John T Scott" initials="J." surname="Scott">
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="April" day="1"/>
    <abstract>This report documents the U.S. federal agencies use of foreign patents, in addition to U.S. patents, to protect the intellectual property for inventions created in their laboratories. The report describes the extent of U.S. and foreign patents in the patent portfolios of the U.S. federal agencies, and it describes the process of licensing of the agencies patented inventions. A dynamic panel data model is estimated for each agency s invention-license revenues as a function of the history of its applications and granted patents. The evidence supports the view that an agency that obtains U.S. patents for its inventions but does not obtain foreign patent protection may reduce the value of licenses to use the technologies. Value for the licensee may be reduced because the corporations that license the agency s technologies may face international competition from firms that copy those technologies and compete with lower costs because they do not incur full development costs or pay royalties for licensing the technologies. The report estimates the agencies benefits, in terms of licensing revenues, and costs for obtaining foreign-patent protection for their U.S.-patented inventions. The report provides detailed case studies of the licensing and commercialization of two federal-agency technologies.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.GCR.20-025"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Grant/Contractor Reports" value="20-025"/>
</reference>