<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1244" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1244">
  <front>
    <title>Research needs concerning the performance of fiber reinforced (FR) composite retrofit systems for buildings and infrastructure</title>
    <author fullname="Goodwin, David.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sattar, Siamak.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dukes, Jazalyn.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kim, Jae Hyun.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ferraris, Chiara.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sung, Li-piin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Throughout the United States, the use of fiber reinforced (FR) composites in building and infrastructure applications has been steadily on the rise. FR composite materials, which include fiber reinforced polymer (FRP) composites and fiber reinforced cementitious matrix (FRCM) composites, are used to repair, strengthen, and seismically retrofit structural components (e.g., columns, beams, walls) of existing buildings and infrastructure. FR composite retrofits have become competitive with more traditional retrofit techniques due to their high strength, light weight, low profile, and corrosion resistance. These FR composite properties have resulted in lower overall costs and more efficient, less labor-intensive installation processes. Furthermore, repair, strengthening, and seismic retrofit of aging structures with FR composites leads to improved building and infrastructure resilience. Since the use of FR composites in the civil engineering field has matured, this report serves to review the state-of-the-art for FR composite performance and identify research needs requisite to advancing the field. The report focuses primarily on externally bonded FRP composites since they are most commonly used in practice in the United States. The research needs were obtained by an extensive literature review and from input received at a national stakeholder workshop at NIST in 2018. The findings of this report describe the materials and structural level research needs prioritized per the subject matter expert opinions received at the workshop. Major materials research needs include improvement of inspector certification processes and improvement or development of test methods that assess the condition of FR composites after installation and long-term use. Other major research needs include identification of bond degradation mechanisms between FRP composites and concrete and relation of accelerated conditioning protocols to long-term exposure outdoors. Structural research needs include development of design standards and guidelines for FR retrofitted components and buildings, improvement of inspection practices, structural-scale experimental studies, and improvement of numerical modeling capabilities. This report is intended to inform future research plans developed by various stakeholders concerning the performance of buildings and infrastructure that are retrofitted or repaired with FR composites.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.1244"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1244"/>
</reference>