<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1900-203" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1900-203">
  <front>
    <title>Global City Teams Challenge Public Safety SuperCluster progress report 2018-2019</title>
    <author fullname="Bannan, Brenda.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dubrow, Samantha.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dunaway, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rhee, Sokwoo.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Skidmore, Dean.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Torres, Elisa.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>NIST co-hosted the 2018-2019 GCTC Smart and Secure Cities and Communities Challenge (SC3) program with DHS S and NTIA. The objective was to encourage participating teams to include cybersecurity and privacy as integral project elements alongside goals such as replicability, scalability, sustainability, and interoperability of technologies and systems. In parallel, GCTC's Public Safety SuperCluster (PSSC) sought to bring together domain experts in public safety to discuss the latest issues and developments and to explore designed-in cybersecurity and privacy for public safety solutions. This report highlights two significant accomplishments of the PSSC: First, this report describes in detail the workshop hosted by PSSC and NIST in October 2018 to address the latest progress and plans of the Public Safety SuperCluster and, further, to initiate an active collaboration with the Cybersecurity and Privacy Advisory Committee (CPAC) to begin incorporating the dimension of cybersecurity into the PSSC effort. This section describes presentations and group discussions around shared perspectives on the latest developments in public safety and cybersecurity for smart cities and communities. The workshop provided a foundation for PSSC's activities in 2019. Secondly, this publication includes a summary of the first in a planned series of reports on use cases, technology demonstrations, and exercise summaries involving the work and outcomes of PSSC Action Clusters and Public Safety-related efforts in GCTC communities. It highlights a significant demonstration in November 2019 of a live simulation-based, multi-team training exercise in Mass Casualty Incident (MCI) response that was conducted by the GCTC research team from the George Mason University in collaboration with Fairfax County, Virginia, first responder agencies.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.1900-203"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1900-203"/>
</reference>