<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1500-15" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1500-15">
  <front>
    <title>Strategic roadmap for interoperable public safety video analytics</title>
    <author fullname="Simpson, Diane.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brennan, Michelle.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gomperts, Susan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Since 9/11, the Department of Homeland Security has provided over $1 6 billion dollars in grant assistance to secure cities and non-profit organizations against terrorist and disaster incidents. In order to meet the threat demands, public safety organizations have increasingly invested in video surveillance systems to increase their patrol footprint and monitor major transportation areas. Many cities now have hundreds to thousands of public safety and transportation infrastructure cameras; larger cities have tens of thousands of these cameras. Public safety now faces a growing diversity of video data sources, and these volumes of data are increasingly vital to public safety operations. However, analysis of video data to support real-time operations largely relies on manual processes and non-security related, impractical physically isolated architectures. The purpose of this publication is to chart a path forward to guide public safety related agencies and individual public safety departments in their transition from a state of interoperability that occurs by chance to a state of institutionalized interoperability which incorporates the next-generation of video analytics through measured steps and broad stakeholder informed decision making</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1500-15"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1500-15"/>
</reference>