<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8441" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8441">
  <front>
    <title>Cybersecurity framework profile for hybrid satellite networks (HSN)</title>
    <author fullname="McCarthy, James.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mamula, Dan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brule, Joseph.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Meldorf, Karri.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jennings, Rory.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wiltberger, John.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thorpe, Chris.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dombrowski, John.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lattin, O’Ryan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sepassi, Sam.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The space sector is transitioning towards Hybrid Satellite Networks (HSN) which is an aggregation of independently owned and operated terminals, antennas, satellites, payloads, or other components that comprise a satellite system. The elements of an HSN may have varying levels of assurance. HSNs may interact with government systems and critical infrastructure (as defined by the Department of Homeland Security). A framework is required to assess the security posture of the individual components while still enabling the HSN to provide its function. This report applies the NIST Cybersecurity Framework to HSNs with an emphasis on the interfaces between the participants of the HSN. In collaboration with subject matter experts including satellite builders, consultants, acquisition authorities, operators (commercial and government), academia, and other interested parties, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has developed the HSN Cybersecurity Framework CSF Profile (HSN Profile) to guide space stakeholders. The resulting profile provides a starting point for stakeholders who are assessing the cybersecurity posture of their HSN.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8441"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8441"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal&#10;                report" value="8441"/>
</reference>