<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8183A-1" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8183A-1">
  <front>
    <title>Cybersecurity framework manufacturing profile low impact level example implementations guide</title>
    <author fullname="Stouffer, Keith.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zimmerman, Timothy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tang, CheeYee.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Cichonski, Jeffrey.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pease, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shah, Neeraj.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Downard, Wesley.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This guide provides general implementation guidance (Volume 1) and example proof-of-concept solutions demonstrating how available open-source and commercial off-the-shelf (COTS) products could be implemented in manufacturing environments to satisfy the requirements in the Cybersecurity Framework (CSF) Manufacturing Profile Low Impact Level. Example proof-ofconcept solutions with measured network, device, and operational performance impacts for a process-based manufacturing environment (Volume 2) and a discrete-based manufacturing environment (Volume 3) are included in the guide. Manufacturers should make their own determinations about the breadth of the proof-of-concept solutions they voluntarily implement. Some important factors to consider include: company size, cybersecurity expertise, risk tolerance, and the threat landscape. The CSF Manufacturing Profile can be used as a roadmap for managing cybersecurity risk for manufacturers and is aligned with manufacturing sector goals and industry best practices. The Manufacturing Profile provides a voluntary, risk-based approach for managing cybersecurity activities and cyber risk to manufacturing systems. The Manufacturing Profile is meant to complement but not replace current cybersecurity standards and industry guidelines that the manufacturer is embracing.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8183A-1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8183A-1"/>
</reference>