<reference anchor="NIST.GCR.02-843-1" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.GCR.02-843-1">
  <front>
    <title>Analysis of needs and existing capabilities for full-scale fire resistance testing</title>
    <author fullname="Beitel, Jesse J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Iwankiw, Nestor.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Hughes Associates.</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Building and Fire Research Laboratory (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The study was commissioned to analyze the needs and existing capabiliites for full-scale fire resistance testing of structural connections. The scope of work consisted of three separate tasks. Task 1. Identification of building collapse incidents: The objective of this Task was to conduct a survey of historical information of fire occurences in multi-story (defined as four or more stories) buildings, which resulted in structural collapse. Either partial or total failure of the structural framing members, and/or connections was considered to hav constituted a collapse. Task 2. Survey of fire resistence test facilities: The objective of this task was to survey private and public facilities (for-profit, not-for-profit; academic, local, state and federal government; military and civilian; domestic and international) capable of testing structural integrity of building elements under fire conditions to establish the current global research capabilities in structural fire protection. Task 3. Needs assessment: the objective of this task was to perform an assessment of the need for additional testing and/or experimental facilities to support the development of predictive structural fire protection methods within actual buildings; and if a need does exist, options for meeting those needs.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.GCR.02-843-1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST GCR; NIST grant-contract report; NIST grant contract report" value="02-843-1"/>
</reference>