<reference anchor="NIST.AMS.300-8" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.AMS.300-8">
  <front>
    <title>Wireless user requirements for the factory workcell</title>
    <author fullname="Montgomery, Karl.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Candell, Richard.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Liu, Yongkang.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hany, Mohamed.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Wireless communication is becoming crucial to advanced manufacturing. Industry 4.0 and SmartManufacturing depend on networked industrial automation systems. The term Industrial Internet ofThings (IIoT) has been used to describe the deployment of interconnected machines, sensors, andactuators within modernized factories. The adoption of wireless systems is essential to these IIoTdeployments. Wireless automation significantly reduces capital investment costs including conduit,cables, networking equipment, and labor of installation. To enable the adoption of wireless systems atthe factory-floor level, wireless requirements must be established to realize the benefits of wirelesscommunication systems within those factories. One challenge is that existing wireless standards lacktechnical specifications that support low-latency and high-reliability communication for factoryapplications. Additionally, requirements for such capabilities are published or advertised withoutvalidation of said requirements. Often, requirements published by standards developmentorganizations appear excessively strict and unvalidated by empirical study. Moreover, thoserequirements ignore the capabilities of the applications to use their own intelligence to compensatefor lost reliability in the network. This report analyzes existing wireless user requirements stated byindustry organizations and it produces a combined perspective on wireless user requirements for thefactory workcell with supporting rationale.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.AMS.300-8"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST advanced manufacturing series; NIST AMS" value="300-8"/>
</reference>