<reference anchor="NIST.VTS.100-2" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-2">
  <front>
    <title>Training poll workers for accessible voting</title>
    <author fullname="Blahovec, Sarah.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Quesenbery, Whitney.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laskowski, Sharon J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Accessible voting systems are a key feature in polling places that enable voters with disabilities to vote privately and independently. The Help America Vote Act of 2002 (HAVA) requires that each polling place have a voting system that is “accessible for individuals with disabilities, including nonvisual accessibility for the blind and visually impaired,” and that it must provide “the same opportunity for access and participation (including privacy and independence) as for other voters.” These systems must be available for all voters, but many voters who are blind or have low vision, voters with mobility disabilities or who lack manual dexterity, and voters with cognitive disabilities need accessible voting systems to vote privately and independently. This report and sample training slide presentation (available for download and modification at https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-2sup1) are intended to assist election officials as they develop their poll worker training to support voters with disabilities at the polling place. This work is in response to the inconsistency of available training materials for poll workers on how to set up accessible voting systems and support voters in using them. In addition to ensuring that poll workers know the legal rules for disability voting rights in the polling place, it includes guidance for helping voters while preserving their independence and privacy.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-2"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST voting technology standard; NIST VTS" value="100-2"/>
</reference>