<reference anchor="NIST.SP.800-181r1es" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.800-181r1es">
  <front>
    <title>Workforce framework for cybersecurity (NICE Framework) (Spanish translation)</title>
    <author fullname="Rodney Petersen" initials="R." surname="Petersen">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Danielle Santos" initials="D." surname="Santos">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matthew C Smith" initials="M." surname="Smith">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Karen A Wetzel" initials="K." surname="Wetzel">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greg Witte" initials="G." surname="Witte">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="February" day="14"/>
    <abstract>This publication describes the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework (NICE Framework), a reference structure that describes the interdisciplinary nature of the cybersecurity work. It serves as a fundamental reference resource for describing and sharing information about cybersecurity work and the knowledge, skills, and abilities (KSAs) needed to complete tasks that can strengthen the cybersecurity posture of an organization. As a common, consistent lexicon that categorizes and describes cybersecurity work, the NICE Framework improves communication about how to identify, recruit, develop, and retain cybersecurity talent. The NICE Framework is a reference source from which organizations or sectors can develop additional publications or tools that meet their needs to define or provide guidance on different aspects of cybersecurity workforce development, planning, training, and education.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.800-181r1es"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="800-181r1es"/>
</reference>