<reference anchor="NIST.TN.1979" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.1979">
  <front>
    <title>NIST channel sounder overview and channel measurements in manufacturing facilities</title>
    <author fullname="Quimby, Jeanne T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Candell, Richard.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Remley, Kate A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Novotný, David.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Diener, Joseph.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Papazian, Peter B.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Curtin, Alexandra.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Koepke, Galen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Manufacturers are increasingly choosing wireless platforms to replace wired ones due to their ease of installation, upgrade, and reconfigurability. Reliable and secure real-time performance of wireless platforms is technically challenging because wireless data communication, reliability, and throughput can be easily affected by the physical environment in which the wireless platforms are operate. These effects need to be investigated and better understood through physics-based modeling, correlated with real-world measurements. To support U.S. manufacturers, the NIST Engineering Laboratory has launched a five-year project entitled Wireless Systems for Industrial Environments as part of the NIST Standards for Manufacturing Systems Program. The key idea for this project is to develop best-practice guidelines for integrated performance evaluation of secure wireless platforms in dynamic production systems. This will include a methodology for selecting wireless technology and protocols that will assure real-time performance of wireless platforms in various manufacturing environments. These guidelines will enable manufacturers, technology providers, and solution providers to design, deploy, and assess robust, secure integrated wireless solutions for use in smart manufacturing. As part of this project, NIST will be characterizing the wireless environment through measurements in representative production facilities.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.TN.1979"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="1979"/>
</reference>