<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2256" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2256">
  <front>
    <title>November 2022 NIST Premise Plumbing Research Workshop</title>
    <author fullname="Persily, Andrew K.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Batista, Marylia Duarte.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Healy, William M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kedzierski, Mark A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lin, Lingnan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Milesi-Ferretti, Natascha S.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ullah, Tania">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yashar, David A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zimmerman, Stephen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Premise plumbing systems need to meet a range of performance goals including occupant health and comfort, energy and water efficiency, and reduced environmental impacts. Pressures to improve water efficiency and building water quality, combined with the use of new plumbing technologies and designs, have led to the recognition that significant knowledge gaps exist in plumbing system design, installation, operation, and maintenance. The research needed to address these gaps was summarized in a 2020 NIST report Measurement Science Research Needs for Premise Plumbing Systems. NIST also initiated an effort in 2020 to study several key research topics identified in that report including: the pressure versus flow relationships of plumbing fittings, the factors contributing to pathogen growth in residential hot water systems, the development of standard plumbing systems for comparing different design and operational approaches, and the improvement of existing premise plumbing system simulation software. To obtain feedback from industry and others in the premise plumbing community, NIST held a one-day workshop in November 2022 to discuss these research efforts, strengthen ongoing dialogues among the plumbing community, and develop a shared understanding of the research needs.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2256"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2256"/>
</reference>