<reference anchor="NIST.HB.130-2024-upd1" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.HB.130-2024-upd1">
  <front>
    <title>Uniform laws and regulations in the areas of legal metrology and fuel quality</title>
    <author fullname="McGuire, John">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sefcik, David.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Warfield, Lisa.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Branden, Yvonne.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lippa, Katrice.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>NIST Handbook 130 includes a compilation of model laws and regulations and related interpretations and guidelines designed to encourage uniformity in adoption and implementation of weights and measures laws and regulations. The model laws and regulations included in NIST Handbook 130 are adopted in various forms by many state, local, and some federal weights and measures authorities. Some authorities adopt the current versions as written; some use them as the basis of adoption, but from an earlier year; some use them as a guideline only; some elect to use their own laws or regulations; and some have no corresponding law or regulation in place.The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has a statutory responsibility to promote "cooperation with the states in securing uniformity in weights and measures laws and method of inspection” and publishes this and other NIST Handbooks in partial fulfillment of this responsibility.This 2024 edition includes amendments made through the Committee on Laws and Regulations of the NCWM with technical guidance from the Office of Weights and Measures (OWM) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and input from weights and measures officials and industry representatives. These amendments were adopted by the NCWM at its 108th Annual Meeting in July 2023.At the 1983 Annual Meeting, the NCWM voted to change the title of Handbook 130 from “Model State Laws and Regulations” was to be changed to “Uniform Laws and Regulations” to reflect that these Laws and Regulations are (a) intended to be standards rather than just guidelines, and (b) intended for adoption by political subdivisions other than states when deemed appropriate. In 1995 the title was changed to Uniform Laws and Regulations in the areas of legal metrology and motor fuel quality. In the 1997 Edition of Handbook 130 was changed from "Uniform Laws and Regulations the words “motor fuel quality" was changed to “engine fuel quality" to reflect changes made to the Uniform Engine Fuels, Petroleum Products, and Automotive Lubricants Law and Regulation. In 2018, the scope of the Fuels regulation was expanded to encompass the changing fuels in the marketplace, and the title to the Handbook was changed to how it appears today.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.HB.130-2024-upd1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST handbook" value="130-2024-upd1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST handbook; NIST HB" value="130-2024-upd1"/>
</reference>