<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1261" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1261">
  <front>
    <title>Economic Decision Guide Software (EDGe) online tutorial</title>
    <author fullname="Helgeson, Jennifer F.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Leibold, Alyssa A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The Coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) global pandemic has raised concerns as to how to best host fall semesters at universities and colleges across the U.S. in the face of high transmission rates. College campuses have a communal structure that may allow for an infectious disease to become a serious issue to students and staff. College campuses are in need of resilience planning that deals with the presence of a pandemic. In this report, four alternatives are evaluated that might assist colleges in mitigating some of the negative economic effects of an infectious disease. The use case presented in this report is fictious and is meant to reflect a public four-year highereducation institution; however, the values used are based on real-life estimates, when available. Costs and benefits were configured for four alternatives and analyzed with the Economic Decision Guide Software (EDGe) Online Tool to determine the relative net present value of these resilience strategies via a benefit-cost analysis (BCA). Though designed to evaluate investments into built infrastructure, EDGe is demonstrated to be applicable to questions of resilience planning more broadly. The results of this use case show that an outdoor facility would be the best alternative for the college campus modeled, given various parameters and assumptions. The outdoor facility allows for the alleviation of all fatalities and has various benefits that include positive externalities and net co-benefits. This use case demonstrates a basic BCA using EDGe Online to determine a community's course of action in planning for pandemics, especially when some alternatives relate to built infrastructure resilience and/or sustainability, e.g., through indirect valuation or cobenefits.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1261"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1261"/>
</reference>