<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8286C" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8286C">
  <front>
    <title>Staging cybersecurity risks for enterprise risk management and governance oversight</title>
    <author fullname="Stephen Quinn" initials="S." surname="Quinn">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nahla Ivy" initials="N." surname="Ivy">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matthew Barrett" initials="M." surname="Barrett">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greg Witte" initials="G." surname="Witte">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="R K K Gardner" initials="R K" surname="Gardner">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="February" day="10"/>
    <abstract>This document is the third in a series that supplements NIST Interagency/Internal Report (NISTIR) 8286, Integrating Cybersecurity and Enterprise Risk Management (ERM). This series provides additional details regarding the enterprise application of cybersecurity risk information; the previous documents, NISTIRs 8286A and 8286B, provided details regarding stakeholder risk direction and methods for assessing and managing cybersecurity risk in light of enterprise objectives. NISTIR 8286C describes how information, as recorded in cybersecurity risk registers (CSRRs), may be integrated as part of a holistic approach to ensuring that risks to information and technology are properly considered for the enterprise risk portfolio. This cohesive understanding supports an enterprise risk register (ERR) and enterprise risk profile (ERP) that, in turn, support the achievement of enterprise objectives.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8286C"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8286C"/>
</reference>