<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1800-10" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1800-10">
  <front>
    <title>Protecting information and system integrity in industrial control system environments :
cybersecurity for the manufacturing sector</title>
    <author fullname="Michael Powell" initials="M." surname="Powell">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Joseph Brule" initials="J." surname="Brule">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Michael Pease" initials="M." surname="Pease">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Keith Stouffer" initials="K." surname="Stouffer">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="CheeYee Tang" initials="C." surname="Tang">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Timothy Zimmerman" initials="T." surname="Zimmerman">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chelsea Deane" initials="C." surname="Deane">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Hoyt" initials="J." surname="Hoyt">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mary Raguso" initials="M." surname="Raguso">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Aslam Sherule" initials="A." surname="Sherule">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kangmin Zheng" initials="K." surname="Zheng">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matthew Zopf" initials="M." surname="Zopf">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="March" day="16"/>
    <abstract>Today's manufacturing organizations rely on industrial control systems (ICS) to conduct their operations. Increasingly, ICS are facing more frequent, sophisticated cyber attacks making manufacturing the second-most-targeted industry. Cyber attacks against ICS threaten operations and worker safety, resulting in financial loss and harm to the organization's reputation. The architecture and solutions presented in this guide are built upon standards-based, commercially available products, and represent some of the possible solutions. The solutions implement standard cybersecurity capabilities such as behavioral anomaly detection (BAD), application allowlisting (AAL), file integrity-checking, change control management, and user authentication and authorization. The solution was tested in two distinct lab settings: a discrete manufacturing workcell, which represents an assembly line production, and a continuous process control system (PCS), which represents chemical manufacturing industries. An organization that is interested in protecting the integrity of a manufacturing system and information from destructive malware, insider threats, and unauthorized software should first conduct a risk assessment and determine the appropriate security capabilities required to mitigate those risks. Once the security capabilities are identified, the sample architecture and solution presented in this document may be used.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.1800-10"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="1800-10"/>
</reference>