<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2096" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2096">
  <front>
    <title>Small punch testing to estimate mechanical properties of additively manufactured Ti-6Al-4V</title>
    <author fullname="Lucon, Enrico.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Benzing, Jake.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hrabe, Nikolas Wilson.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Small Punch (SP) testing is a methodology that uses small disk-shaped specimens, generally 8 mm in diameter and 0.5 mm thick, to estimate mechanical properties of metallic materials, such as tensile properties, fracture toughness, and ductile-to-brittle transition temperature. Empirical correlations are typically used to infer conventional mechanical properties from characteristic forces and displacements obtained from the test record. Most of the available literature relates to SP testing of steels, while relatively little information is available for other metallic materials. At NIST in Boulder, Colorado, SP tests were conducted on additively manufactured (AM) Ti-6Al-4V with different processing parameters and heat treatment conditions. The shape of force/punch displacement curves appeared different than typically reported for conventionally manufactured steels, and correlations with tensile parameters were generally weaker than those published for steel samples. We are led to conclude that the application of the SP technique, characterized by a biaxial loading mode, to materials with high anisotropy, such as current batches of AM Ti-6Al-4V, may be somewhat problematic and therefore of limited applicability. Finally, the use of actuator displacement instead of punch displacement in test analyses appeared to cause a generalized worsening of the correlations.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.TN.2096"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2096"/>
</reference>