<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8395" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8395">
  <front>
    <title>Low-GWP alternative refrigerant blends for HFC-134a</title>
    <author fullname="Domanski, Piotr A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McLinden, Mark O.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Babushok, Valeri I.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bell, Ian H.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fortin, Tara J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hegetschweiler, Michael J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kedzierski, Mark A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kim, Dennis K.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lin, Lingnan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Linteris, Gregory T.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Outcalt, Stephanie L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Perkins, Richard A.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rowane, Aaron">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Skye, Harrison">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This project addresses the objectives of the Statement of Need number WPSON-17-20 No/Low Global Warming Potential Alternatives to Ozone Depleting Refrigerants. Its goal is to identify and demonstrate performance of low global-warming-potential (GWP), non-flammable refrigerants to replace HFC-134a in military environmental control units (ECUs). This project is a follow-on to the limited-scope project WP-2740, which used thermodynamic cycle simulation models alone to screen over 100 000 refrigerant blends and identified over 20 candidate HFC-134a replacements. In this study we narrow the pool of blend candidates down to three best fluids, verify experimentally their flammability behavior, demonstrate their performance through tests in a military ECU in environmental chambers at a wide range of operating conditions, and extrapolate the laboratory measured performance to ECUs equipped with optimized heat exchangers through first-principles-based simulations combined with machine-learning optimization methods. This Interim Report documents the preliminary work leading to the selection of three best blends. This work included refrigerant blend tests in a laboratory mini-breadboard heat pump apparatus, fundamental measurements and modeling of thermophysical properties, two-phase heat-transfer performance, and flammability behavior.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8395"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8395"/>
</reference>