<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8324" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8324">
  <front>
    <title>2018 Media Forensics Challenges (MFC18)</title>
    <author fullname="Lee, Yooyoung.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yates, Amy N.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Guan, Haiying.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Delgado, Andrew.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhou, Daniel.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kheyrkhah, Timothee.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fiscus, Jonathan.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The interest in forensic techniques capable of detecting many different media manipulation types has been growing, and system development with machine learning technology has been evolving in recent years. There has been, however, a lack of diversity in the data collections and in the evaluation methodologies for advancing multimedia forensics technologies. For the forensics research community, a well-defined evaluation is necessary to rapidly measure the accuracy and robustness of systems over diverse datasets collected under various environments. In this paper, we propose an evaluation framework and associated performance metrics and apply them to the 2018 Multimedia Forensics Challenge (MFC18). This MFC18 evaluation consists of five tasks and two challenges. A large number of datasets were created to support each task and for conducting the experiments using a structured evaluation framework. A total of 25 teams participated in the MFC18 evaluation; we analyse their performance on the tasks and challenges, and provide performance rankings for each team’s best-performing system.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.IR.8324"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR" value="8324"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8324"/>
</reference>