<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2290" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2290">
  <front>
    <title>Report on high energy arcing fault experiments</title>
    <author fullname="Putorti Jr, Anthony D.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bareham, Scott.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brown, Christopher U.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tam, Wai Cheong.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Heck, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fox, Lucy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fink, Stephen.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Selepak, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hnetkovsky, Edward.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Melly, Nicholas.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hamburger, Kenneth.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Miller, Kenneth.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This report documents an experimental program designed to collect data and information to evaluate the performance of models developed to estimate the electrical high energy arcing fault (HEAF) hazard. This report covers full-scale laboratory experiments using representative nuclear power plant (NPP) three-phase electrical equipment. Equipment included medium-voltage metal-enclosed bus ducts and switchgear and low-voltage metal-enclosed switchgear. Electrical, thermal, and pressure data were recorded for each experiment and documented in this report. The experiments include five medium-voltage switchgear, two medium-voltage non-segregated bus ducts, and three low-voltage switchgear. These experiments differed from past programs in that the effects to adjacent and nearby equipment were also evaluated. The data collected supports characterization of the HEAF hazard, and these results will be used to complement the data used for HEAF hazard modeling tools and support potential improvements in fire probabilistic risk assessment (PRA) methods.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2290"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2290"/>
</reference>