<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8252" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8252">
  <front>
    <title>IREX IX part two</title>
    <author fullname="Quinn, George W.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Grother, Patrick J.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matey, James.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Iris Exchange (IREX) IX is an evaluation of automated iris recognition algorithms. The first part of the evaluation was a performance test of both verification (one-to-one) and identification (one-to-many) recognition algorithms over operational test data. Those results are summarized in NIST IR 8207. The second part of the evaluation constitutes a multispectral evaluation of iris recognition. Those results are summarized in this report. All currently deployed iris recognition systems operate on images of the iris illuminated in the near infrared band of the electromagnetic spectrum. The ISO/IEC 19794-6 and 29794-6 standards require the eye to be illuminated between 'approximately 700 and 900 nanometers (nm)'. Near infrared light is specified because melanin, the pigment that makes dark eyes dark, is nearly transparent in the near infrared. This evaluation assesses the accuracy of state-of-the-art iris matchers over a much wider range of the spectrum. Particular attention is placed on the visible (400 nm to 700 nm) and short wave infrared (700 nm to 1550 nm) bands. Principle testing was performed over the Consolidated Multispectral Iris Dataset (CMID) which was provided to NIST by the Southern Methodist University. Collected in well controlled laboratory settings, the dataset is ideal for multispectral analysis. It contains about a quarter-million iris samples from over 200 subjects, by far the largest of its kind as of this writing. Thirteen research institutions submitted matching algorithms for testing.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8252"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal report" value="8252"/>
</reference>