<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2288" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2288">
  <front>
    <title>NIST eave and vent experiments (EaVE) EaVEs phase A</title>
    <author fullname="Brown, Christopher U.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Maranghides, Alexander.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nazare, Shonali.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Di Cristina, Giovanni.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bailey, D. Michelle.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fox, Lucy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Link, Eric.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ramesh, Selvarajah.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Monroy, Xareni.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Miller, J. Houston.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McCaughey, Erin E.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Flores, Monica M.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This test plan documents experiments that are part of ongoing research to assess structure-to-structure fire spread in the Wildland-Urban Interface (WUI). Previous indoor and outdoor full-scale experiments were conducted with varying distance between sheds and the exterior wall of a primary residence. The current experiments were planned to understand the failure of the eave vents used in previous experiments. The objective of these full-scale experiments is to characterize the performance of representative eave vents exposed to fire from the source structure. Metal sheds of varying sizes and fuel loads (wood cribs) will be burned under the 20 MW exhaust hood in the National Fire Research Laboratory (NFRL) at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) at varying structure separation distances (SSDs) from the target structure. The target structure includes an assembly of an exterior wall, a roof, and an eave vent. A range of measurements will be taken during the experiments including heat release rate, heat flux, temperature, gas flow velocity, and gas species concentration using open-path absorption spectroscopy. Video and infrared cameras will record the experiments. A separate NIST Technical Note will report the results of these experiments.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.TN.2288"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST technical note; NIST tech note; NIST TN" value="2288"/>
</reference>