<reference anchor="NIST.SP.1236" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.1236">
  <front>
    <title>Large outdoor fires and the built environment</title>
    <author fullname="Manzello, Samuel L.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="McAllister, Sara.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Suzuki, Sayaka.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Blanchi, Raphaele.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pastor, Elsa.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Enrico, Ronchi.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.).</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>The kickoff workshop of the new permanent working group, sponsored by the International Association for Fire Safety Science (IAFSS), entitled Large Outdoor Fires and the Built Environment was held from 3:00 pm to 4:30 pm on Sunday October 21, 2018. The workshop was held as a part of the 11th Asia-Oceania Symposium on Fire Science and Technology (AOSFST) in Taipei, Taiwan. The working group is co-led by Sara McAllister of the U.S. Forest Service (unable to come to Taiwan), Sayaka Suzuki of National Research Institute of Fire and Disaster, and Samuel L. Manzello of NIST's Engineering Laboratory. The IAFSS permanent working group consists of three subgroups, with subleaders appointed by Manzello, McAllister, and Suzuki, and these are prioritized into the following topics: Ignition Resistant Communities (IRC, led by Elsa Pastor, UPC, unable to come to Taiwan), Emergency Management and Evacuation (EME, led by Enrico Ronchi, Lund University, unable to come to Taiwan), and Large Outdoor Firefighting (LOFF, led by Raphaele Blanchi, CSIRO). The IRC subgroup is focused on developing the scientific basis for new standard testing methodologies indicative of large outdoor fire exposures, including the development of necessary testing methodologies to characterize wildland fuel treatments adjacent to communities. The EME subgroup is focused on developing the scientific basis for effective emergency management strategies for communities exposed to large outdoor fires. The LOFF subgroup is providing a review of various tactics that are used, as well as the various personal protective equipment (PPE), and suggest pathways for research community engagement, including environmental issues in suppressing these fires. The overall objectives are to bring the full depth of knowledge of the IAFSS community to work on these priority topics. At the kickoff workshop, detailed ideas were presented regarding the planned activities of the working group, especially the large workshop to be held at IAFSS 2020.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="NIST.SP.1236"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST special publication; NIST special pub; NIST SP" value="1236"/>
</reference>