<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8219" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8219">
  <front>
    <title>Securing manufacturing industrial control systems</title>
    <author fullname="McCarthy, James.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Powell, Michael.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stouffer, Keith.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tang, CheeYee.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zimmerman, Timothy.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Barker, William.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ogunyale, Titilayo.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wynne, Devin.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Wiltberger, Johnathan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory (National Institute of Standards and Technology)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>Industrial control systems (ICS) are used in many industries to monitor and control physical processes. As ICS continue to adopt commercially available information technology (IT) to promote corporate business systems- connectivity and remote access capabilities, ICS become more vulnerable to cybersecurity threats. The National Institute of Standards and Technology's (NIST's) National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence (NCCoE), in conjunction with NIST's Engineering Laboratory (EL), has demonstrated a set of behavioral anomaly detection capabilities to support cybersecurity in manufacturing organizations. These capabilities enable manufacturers to detect anomalous conditions in their operating environments to mitigate malware attacks and other threats to the integrity of critical operational data. NIST's NCCoE and EL have mapped these demonstrated capabilities to the Cybersecurity Framework and have documented how this set of standards-based controls can support many of the security requirements of manufacturers. This report documents the use of behavioral anomaly detection (BAD) capabilities in two distinct but related demonstration environments: a robotics-based manufacturing system and a process control system that resembles what is being used by chemical manufacturing industries.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8219"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NISTIR; NIST IR; NIST interagency report; NIST internal&#10;                report" value="8219"/>
</reference>