<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8363" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8363">
  <front>
    <title>Examining recent HR data for gender bias among federal employees at NIST</title>
    <author fullname="Jasmine Evans" initials="J." surname="Evans">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Amanda Koepke" initials="A." surname="Koepke">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Steven Lund" initials="P" surname="Lund">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mary Theofanos" initials="F" surname="Theofanos">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="March" day="26"/>
    <abstract>This report is part of a multi-phase mixed methods project that is designed to provide an in-depth look at the population of National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) federal employees to identify factors, attitudes, and processes that might result in genderspecific barriers at NIST. In the current project phase, human resources demographic data, compensation data, and performance data of NIST federal employees from 2011 to 2019 were analyzed to determine any relevant trends. This report details the methodology and results, including the steps of analysis, and summarizes where NIST currently stands regarding workplace gender differences. The results include trends of gender differences in the areas of hiring, pay band, annual salary, and supervisory level. Further analysis identified the highest degree earned as a factor toward gender-specific barriers. Finally, we identified the broken rung as a factor limiting advancement of women.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8363"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8363"/>
</reference>