<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8286D" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8286D">
  <front>
    <title>Using business impact analysis to inform risk prioritization and response</title>
    <author fullname="Stephen Quinn" initials="S." surname="Quinn">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nahla Ivy" initials="N." surname="Ivy">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Julie Chua" initials="J." surname="Chua">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matthew Barrett" initials="M." surname="Barrett">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Larry Feldman" initials="L." surname="Feldman">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Daniel Topper" initials="D." surname="Topper">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greg Witte" initials="G." surname="Witte">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="R K K Gardner" initials="R K" surname="Gardner">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="November" day="17"/>
    <abstract>While business impact analysis (BIA) has historically been used to determine availability requirements for business continuity, the process can be extended to provide a broad understanding of the potential impacts of any type of loss on the enterprise mission. The management of enterprise risk requires a comprehensive understanding of mission-essential functions (i.e., what must go right) and the potential risk scenarios that jeopardize those functions (i.e., what might go wrong). The process described in this publication helps leaders determine which assets enable the achievement of mission objectives and evaluate the factors that render assets as critical and sensitive. Based on those factors, enterprise leaders provide risk directives (i.e., risk appetite and tolerance) as input to the BIA. System owners then apply the BIA to developing asset categorization, impact values, and requirements for the protection of critical or sensitive assets. The output of the BIA is the foundation for the ERM/CSRM process, as described in the NIST IR 8286 series, and enables consistent prioritization, response, and communication regarding information security risk.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8286D"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8286D"/>
</reference>