<reference anchor="NIST.TN.2145" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.TN.2145">
  <front>
    <title>Urban greenhouse gas measurements :urban testbed systems and international cooperation workshop summary report</title>
    <author fullname="Hratch G Semerjian" initials="H." surname="Semerjian">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="James R Whetstone" initials="J." surname="Whetstone">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="April" day="21"/>
    <abstract>On January 30-31, 2020, a workshop was held at NIST in Gaithersburg, MD to review recent developments in measurement capabilities and technologies addressing urban GHG emissions, to assess the state of the art and remaining scientific challenges, and to identify ways to serve the needs of the specific stakeholders, including large municipalities where mitigation actions are planned or underway. Plenary lectures provided an overview of current research activities and capabilities. Panel discussions were held on scientific and technical successes, and knowledge gaps, on researchers' experiences with domestic and international stakeholders, and on ways to map technical capabilities to stakeholder needs. During the discussions over the two-day workshop, there were several themes that workshop participants emphasized about the scientific accomplishments of the community and the remaining technical challenges. Synopses of the presentations are given and summarized. An executive summary gives an overview of the conclusions of the workshop. Appendices include copies of the plenary and supporting presentations made.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.TN.2145"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Technical Notes" value="2145"/>
</reference>