<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8408.ipd" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8408.ipd">
  <front>
    <title>Understanding Stablecoin Technology and Related Security Considerations</title>
    <author fullname="Peter Mell" initials="P." surname="Mell">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dylan Yaga" initials="D." surname="Yaga">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="October" day="5"/>
    <abstract>Stablecoins are cryptocurrencies whose price is pegged to that of another asset (typically one with low price volatility). The market for stablecoins has grown tremendously – up to almost $200 billion USD in 2022. These coins are being used extensively in newly developing paradigms for digital money and commerce as well as for decentralized finance technology. This work provides a technical description of stablecoin technology to enable reader understanding of the variety of ways in which stablecoins are architected and implemented. This includes a descriptive definition, commonly found properties, and distinguishing characteristics, as well as an exploration of stablecoin taxonomies, descriptions of the most common types, and examples from a list of top stablecoins by market capitalization. This document also explores related security, safety, and trust issues with an analysis conducted from a computer science and information technology security perspective as opposed to the financial analysis and economics focus of much of the stablecoin literature.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8408.ipd"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8408"/>
</reference>