<reference anchor="NIST.SP.500-334" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.500-334">
  <front>
    <title>Contactless fingerprint capture and data interchange best practice recommendation</title>
    <author fullname="Shahram Orandi" initials="S." surname="Orandi">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Craig Watson" initials="C." surname="Watson">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Libert" initials="M" surname="Libert">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gregory Fiumara" initials="P" surname="Fiumara">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Grantham" initials="D" surname="Grantham">
      <organization>Information Technology Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="March" day="11"/>
    <abstract>While contactless fingerprint capture devices stand to provide for many benefits, images from this nascent technology are sufficiently different than traditional contact-collected images thereby warranting the separation of these new contactless fingerprint images from legacy contact-collected images and systems operating on them. This Best Practices Recommendation defines voluntary (informative) changes to the ANSI/NIST standard to allow for the creation of contactless transactions that are not readily ingestible by existing systems, but based closely on ANSI/NIST so that minimal changes to the system can allow for processing. Furthermore, the transactions can include the original sensor data, in addition to the contact-compatible/interoperable image in the event that vendors improve their technologies and allow for the reprocessing of the data without recapturing.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.SP.500-334"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publications (General)" value="500-334"/>
</reference>