<reference anchor="NIST.VTS.100-3pt1" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-3pt1">
  <front>
    <title>Usability and accessibility of electronic pollbooks</title>
    <author fullname="Quesenbery, Whitney.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Baumeister, Lynn.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dawkins, Shanée.">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
    </author>
    <abstract>This report explores the use of electronic pollbooks (e-pollbooks) in elections. The scope of this report is on usability and accessibility of e-pollbooks, that is, their use by poll workers and voters, rather than on technical features or costs. This document reports on the use of e-pollbooks in the U.S.; their software, hardware, and interface design, usability, and evaluation. Also presented are the processes in which e-pollbooks are used and state laws encouraging or prohibiting their use. Research described in this report was conducted in 2017. The use of e-pollbooks presented throughout the document reflects the state of elections in 2017. In the time since this research was performed, e-pollbooks have made progress addressing usability and accessibility issues. Additionally, as part of its ongoing Election Supporting Technology Evaluation Program (ESTEP) program, the Election Assistance Commission developed the Voluntary Electronic Poll Book Requirements (VEPBR) in collaboration with NIST. This publication is intended to provide a deep dive into how to evaluate the usability and accessibility of e-pollbooks in order to meet the relevant VEPBR user-centered design process and usability testing requirements as well as any state certifications pertaining to usability and accessibility.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.VTS.100-3pt1"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST voting technology standard; NIST VTS" value="100-3pt1"/>
</reference>