<reference anchor="NIST.IR.8286B" target="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.IR.8286B">
  <front>
    <title>Prioritizing cybersecurity risk for enterprise risk management</title>
    <author fullname="Stephen Quinn" initials="S." surname="Quinn">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nahla Ivy" initials="N." surname="Ivy">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matthew Barrett" initials="M." surname="Barrett">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greg Witte" initials="G." surname="Witte">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="R K K Gardner" initials="R K" surname="Gardner">
      <organization>Material Measurement Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology (U.S.)</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <city>Gaithersburg</city>
          <country>US</country>
          <region>MD</region>
        </postal>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="February" day="10"/>
    <abstract>This document is the second in a series that supplements NIST Interagency/Internal Report (NISTIR) 8286, Integrating Cybersecurity and Enterprise Risk Management (ERM). This series provides additional detail regarding the enterprise application of cybersecurity risk information; the previous document, NISTIR 8286A, provided detail regarding stakeholder risk guidance and risk identification and analysis. This second publication describes the need for determining the priorities of each of those risks in light of their potential impact on enterprise objectives, as well as options for properly treating that risk. This report describes how risk priorities and risk response information are added to the cybersecurity risk register (CSRR) in support of an overall enterprise risk register. Information about the selection of and projected cost of risk response will be used to maintain a composite view of cybersecurity risks throughout the enterprise, which may be used to confirm and, if necessary, adjust risk strategy to ensure mission success.</abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.6028/NIST.IR.8286B"/>
  <seriesInfo name="NIST IR (Interagency/Internal Reports)" value="8286B"/>
</reference>